Uh I just think [music] authentic
intelligence means uh being able to
deliver solutions more so closely to the
level a human word like more so in in
alignment with like AI uh perspective
really brings about enabling current LLM
based models would be to bring in the
appropriate context. context is
important. Context is the right to what
diseases they had in past uh you know
like the age the demographics and so on.
Right? That's sort of the first data
point
that
I want to welcome you to the Signal Room
podcast. Uh for our listeners, we are
live at Planet Hollywood in Las Vegas,
Nevada for the data first conference. We
are here talking about all things AI,
ethical use of AI, uh machine learning.
It's it's the buzzword of the day kind
of conference. I kind I think but I just
want to welcome you Keshavan Seshadri. Uh
Keshavan is the senior machine learning
engineer for Prudential Financial. um
for people who don't really understand
what that means, maybe tell us a little
bit about, you know, what what do you do
in your role and then we'll kind of get
into some topics that are top of mind
for you.
Uh like you said, I work on pretty much
everything that's exciting. Uh and AI
being the buzzword. Uh I work on the
right in the center of it. Uh I work on
building machine learning platforms, uh
generative AI based solutions and like
agent frameworks and anything that
anything that's new, right? and I work
on that. Yeah,
you you're not hiding your excitement. I
like that. It is exciting work. I think
people are a little bit fearful of it,
but I think conversations like where
we're having today are important because
it starts to help people to to
understand the only thing to be fearful
of is not learning honestly. And so the
topic we decided to talk about is
authentic intelligence and designing AI
that understands context. This is a
little bit of a nuance that I don't
typically have hear from a machine
learning expert about, but if you don't
mind, could you talk about authentic
intelligence and what does that really
mean to you and how is it different from
artificial intelligence? Uh I just think
authentic intelligence means uh being
able to deliver solutions more so
closely to the level a human word like
more so in alignment with like AGI uh
perspective right and the uh and what
really brings about enabling current LLM
based models uh would be to bring in the
appropriate context which is where uh
we're at right and this involves both
like short-term memory context and then
there's like like long-term memory
context as well and um I think in this
field right like in in terms of
healthcare context is one of the most
important things because there are like
different types of context one could uh
bring about uh and like when you do
design any sort of AI solution be it
like an agantic AI or an uh like most an
autonomous AI system right um context is
important context is thing.
Yeah, totally. I mean, you you mentioned
the healthcare field um and clinical and
administrative workflows, where does
context break down the most, do you
think? And how can AI be designed to
recognize its own limits,
right? So, in terms of healthcare,
right, like I I see four different types
of uh context that one could bring
about. The first itself being like the
patient context, right? like the um
their health records uh their sort of
like the what diseases they had in the
past and uh you know like the age the
demographics and so on right that's sort
of the first data point like you could
give the LLMS context uh and then uh
there is this another um interesting
context is about like if you were uh
doing a task right like be it diagnosis
or um you know you're doing maybe uh
you're working on something else in in
healthare here like maybe in in
assisting with surgery each of the task
itself has a different uh context
right
right uh and like different set of ways
to go about performing that task and
then there's another uh context which
would be in terms of if I were to
diagnose something today right like do I
have the doctors and my uh doctors near
me or like you know doctors in the
hospital available right now to actually
you know help with the diagn nosis or
like you know finalizing the surgery or
be any task right so you need a human in
the loop as well right and and you also
need to tell the LLM or the AI model
which doctors are available right now
and which uh ones could I bring in to
help me solve the problem and then
there's another context which is in
terms of like uh compliance and
regulations and u institutional context
right like each hospital has their own
set of policies um and then there's
governmental regulations and uh
compliance requirements as well. So
there's like four different types of
context one could uh bring in within
like healthcare.
Yeah, you you touched on the compliance
area and there's there's a lot of
apprehension in I fear honestly out
there um particularly in the in the
medical profession just because a
clinician understands studied for
context probably better than than most
people. It's it's just that the training
that they've had for years. Um they know
inherently
where to go to to find, you know,
specific types of um resources. Um
based on all their training, it could be
their studies or research that they've
done, but that may not be an obvious
thing for a machine or an algorithm to
even deal with. uh talk about how you
see this capability kind of u coming
alongside in assisting a clinician and
how can we use use it in ways that we're
enabling judgment and and how do you
design do do you for your perspective
are you designing um first by having
these conversations and doing some
research along with some clinicians or I
mean how do you see things evolving in a
way that can actually be meaningful
where adoption becomes just a natural
part of the process as opposed to it's a
sales pitch that you have to give your
physicians to try to use it and you can
trust it. uh I mean obviously working
with the physicians and like collecting
the data, collecting all those uh you
know doctor patient conversations and
you know whatever is uh allowed right
like collecting all that data and
figuring out a way to train the model
right uh sometimes right like the
general purpose LLMs might not really be
up to the task right like say for
diagnosis
um it needs more context and context
could be given to the LLM post training
or pre-training itself, right? Like
before I train the model or like while I
train the model, I sort of give the um
necessary context that it understands
like what is a disease and like how do
you diagnose the disease and like what
sort of symptoms you need to look at and
so on, right? This is something that
could be uh given uh as data before even
like working on the model, right? Before
like training the model, right? So maybe
we can think of uh this as like creating
new LLMs or new models, new AI models to
uh help with different tasks, right? And
another way we could think about is like
fine-tuning or context engineering in
this uh case, right? like bringing in
the necessary context to a more general
purpose advanced reasoning LLM like you
know the GPD models or right and and
giving that context while um it's making
the decision or like making the sort of
uh make trying to understand the problem
right
you you touched on something that I
think is really worth d you know digging
a little bit into
physicians get the b the basic core
foundational training and then they
specialize right um your cardio
iothoracic surgeon is not likely
stepping over to do the endocrinologist
job and vice versa. um when you're
talking about you know some of this
nuance and the way you're developing
these models what do what do you think
is take it's going to take to develop
models that are really built in such a
way that it really supports these
I I don't want to call them structures
but basically there's they're almost
subverticals underneath the the the
clinical profession of of a physician.
So how do you think about that and and
do you think it's going to be something
where we're going to basically for every
specialty or sub specialty we're going
to have specialized large language
models that would support those
workloads?
Yeah. So if you see right like let's go
back let's take a step back and like see
how humans do it right now right like
humans have uh or like the doctors they
take a more general course for first few
years and then uh they sort of like do
some sort of residency training and like
um you know figure out how to work
within the hospital right like and then
they choose a specialty and then they uh
repeat the process right and the the
training sort of takes about 10 15
years. Uh that's what I heard. Uh like
good doctors even keep on studying until
like late 40s rush. So
So they're not interested in just
assuming your AI is going to be ready to
go then. Huh.
Yeah. So AI is not going to be, you
know, the specialized doctor that you're
looking for, but it could certainly help
with like more general purpose um like
at least the current models that we have
like the general uh purpose models,
right? Like they could be more so like a
you know uh a student in the university,
right? Like it's I feel like a
university grad or something, right?
Like uh not yet a doctor,
right? uh and we do need like
specialized models but even then there's
like a chance of error right so I
wouldn't really call AI as a doctor at
the moment or like at least in the next
few years it takes a bit more and like
we need to build like mechanisms for
eval mechanisms for guardrails and
right
uh it takes more uh time. Yeah.
Yeah. I I think supporting human
judgment is a really good way to think
about it and probably the safest place
we can we can stay focused on in the
near term. Um who knows what things are
going to evolve. I'm hearing discussion
about things like super intelligence and
like super artificial intelligence. I
thought what we're doing right now is
pretty remarkable. I'm not sure if I'm
ready for for this for these advanced
things that people are thinking about.
But if they're already thinking about it
and talking about it, I'm going to guess
it won't be long before we start
learning a lot.
I it's a it's definitely a time to be
paying attention and and learning what
we can know and figuring out how we can
use it to our advantage. Uh if you're
thinking about the balance of efficiency
and automation,
um
how do you think we account for the
built-in checkpoints where we're looking
for human judgment? Because when you're
talking about it needs to be designed
with context, it also kind of needs to
know when a human being needs to get
involved or provide guidance or judgment
call or whatever. I mean, how do you
think about that? And how do you build
that into your models um that you're
working on so that there's deliberate
stopping points? Because I've noticed
generative AI in particular, unless you
asking it to prompt and ask you
questions, it assumes you're telling it
what it needs to know.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I mean, right now the
models, right, like work based on
probability, right? like it just
predicts the next token and not even
like a next word mode like a next
subword uh like all these LLMs right um
so and then it assigns sort of like a
score right
uh which word should come next right
it's essentially doing that
like an advanced version of what Google
did a decade ago to us finishing our
sentences
yeah yeah it's pretty much doing uh
something like that right um it's not
yet at a stage where it can completely
understand what it's doing right at
least with the models that we have right
now. So uh in terms of like relating
back to your question um like when you
do design these models right like the AI
models you need to build like an eval
set like you need to give how uh or like
have a mechanism or guardrails in place
when to you know defer to a human right
like that's dependent on the score like
a confidence metric that we can uh put
in place right like maybe if it is uh if
the confidence score is greater than 0.9
or like it's then you're pretty good to
go, right? But like when it and also it
depends on the risk, right? In terms of
saying a patient has cancer when he
doesn't really have uh that's okay. But
like uh that just leads to an extra bit
of tests and like you know you have to
um you know get like you have to order
in more tests and that might become
expensive for the patient, right? Like
so that's okay. Uh that's like okay in
the sense uh okay to an extent uh versus
like if you say a person you know
doesn't have cancer when they have when
they do actually have cancer that's even
worse right like missing a diagnosis.
Yeah. And hopefully we're smart enough
to know that we cannot let our AI models
of any kind automatically make a
decision and drive outreach and
communication.
Of course we have a human in the loop.
Um it's just like the first trial right
like even when you you know sort of give
those uh decisions or like you know the
AI uh judgment you also need to include
sort of a confidence score on like a
risk metric um so that like when the
human looks at it it the human
understands right like the AI probably
tried to do a good job but couldn't
right uh based on the current patients
current reports or like their models
underlying knowledge um so pretty much
like uh giving the human a metric to
look upon
right
so they could uh evaluate the answers
from the AI model that I think that u
that's what we need so this comes back
to like precision versus recall versus
like different other metrics that um you
can potentially include
yeah I mean it's interesting you
mentioned recall it's one of the things
I got excited about you know early on
and you know one of my good friends is
here um actually he's working on some
things behind me he's he's a physician
my training and um he pointed out very
wisely to me when I was excited about
having the ability to perfectly recall
things that sometimes uh the things that
we have learned experientially aren't
found in documentation and therefore a
might might not even know about it. So
the fact I can remember something that I
that I documented a decade ago may not
actually be relevant what I think it is
from from a if I'm just thinking about
it from an algorithm standpoint and what
AI is actually going to refer to because
it's just happens to be there and it's
in the model. Um it kind of leads me
into another topic kind of around the
you know it's bias but not not the kind
of bias people typically think about.
It's like what does AI not know about
that's causing it to perceive and answer
prompts in a certain way.
Yeah. So AI is trained on data and like
the large language models more so
commonly are trained on like uh the
entire internet. Right. Right. Uh entire
internet the books like pretty much
anything you can crawl upon you they'll
train on a lot of difference. Right.
Yeah. So it's like if you put in good
stuff in like in in in terms of like the
training the model um good data then
like you get good results right if you
put garbage in then there's garbage out
right so it's essentially that
it's a so when you're dealing with that
you know the bias piece of it but then I
think about how that that can impact
things like explanability right and
there's a there's a fair amount of
legislation that's that's already come
to fruition. I know there's a lot passed
in California recently around requiring
transparency for healthcare providers
are actually using it. Um but the second
piece of that was not just the
transparency but it has to be
explainable. Um which is different in
healthcare because we really do need to
make sure that we're providing enough
understanding so a patient can make an
informed decision around whether they
want to have their data being used that
way. um as you're thinking about, you
know, the things that you're designing,
you're building, and people that you're
you're working with, how do you all
think about really building in the
ability to address this right from the
outset? So, it seems like after you've
delivered the the the first product, um
it might be a little late to have
thought about how do you make it not
only transparent but explainable because
I mean you've been very uh articulate
and easy to understand for me so far,
but I I would be willing to bet that if
you start telling me the real details of
the work you're doing, you would lose me
completely.
I mean, and not so much like it all
sounds fancy, but it's actually really
quite simple to understand. It's not uh
that difficult. And uh in terms of
explanability at least, right, like you
need to work it along with the design,
right? Like when you do design an AI
system, right? Like not just like an LLM
or like a model, right? But like an an
entire AI system, an autonomous AI agent
or something of that sort, you need to
factor in explanability and transparency
while building that model, right? like
they need to have proper logging, proper
uh ways to you know have LLM as a judge,
have LLM, you know, go and like try to
explain me why it took a decision, what
tools did it call, what agents did it
call and so on, right? Like this is sort
of what goes behind the explanability
and uh and showing that explanability to
the user is what brings in the
transparency as well,
right? Um and also it addresses bias
because if there was bias in the
decision making right like and the AI is
able to explain that it had like sort of
a bias when there's another uh agent or
a human that looks at the explain uh uh
looks at what they explained and then
figures out there's some sort of bias in
the decision right they could
potentially flag it right um and then
then you don't really show it to the
user if there's like bias in the testing
mating, right? So, um, and like there's
another way to think about bias itself.
Um, you could have potentially feedback
loops,
okay?
All right. That like when a user or like
a human or another AI flags a particular
response, the feedback is sent back and
it is sent back to the model and it sort
of like fine-tunes it itself. Right.
Right. Uh so this is like uh this is
called like reinforcement learning based
on human feedback right so it's pretty
much what like uh most of these AI
systems are now trying to uh build yeah
I want to ask you to maybe tell on
yourself a little bit or maybe not maybe
it's telling on someone else I don't
know uh but can you think of a moment
where an algorithm produced an insight
that was technically correct but
contextually it was for
um you
and what and I guess where I'm going
with that is is there something that you
can point to that just gave you an
insight about um human and machine
collaboration and why it's so critical
because you could get the right answer
but delivering it in the wrong context
could be really a really bad thing. I'll
give you a real example that probably
people would remember was a number of
years ago. Um there was some capability
that was driving some patient engagement
of activities.
The father got alerted because his
daughter had purchased a pregnancy test
at a pharmacy. Um right information
contact was not so good. It would have
been better. It's handled a little bit
more sensitively. So this this young
woman didn't get direct communication.
It went to her parents. uh no
opportunity for any kind of u healthy
exchange in a way that would have made
the girl feel safe having the
conversation. Um it's kind of nuanced
and it's definitely about the human
relationship part of it. But that's kind
of what I'm thinking about and are there
things that you can you can think of
where you've where you've seen that okay
right answer but
yeah yeah uh I don't know if you've used
chat GPD nowadays right like uh what it
does is it sort of acts like you know
more so personal right like it talks to
you and like it tries to understand what
you are and like has a short term or
sort of memory stored about you right
like and and every answer right like
every answer that the model gives It
ties it back to that uh like ties it
back to what you are right. Right. So
maybe I ask a scientific question like
what happens if uh you consume so and so
during pregnancy right? It might be it
might be that like the AI answers it
like based on textual facts but then
actually telling it to the you know uh
to the person asking the question that
that might not be the best approach
right like right it might be insensitive
or we don't really know right like the
answer could potentially cause like
negative feelings or negative impact
which we don't want as like the people
who design AI we want people to have
like a positive impact on the world and
like
right that's pretty pretty much why uh
you know we want to design AI rights. uh
and we when we do design these systems
we want to bring in that human uh feel
or human touch as well like when we
cannot potentially rely on AI to bring
in that human touch we need a human
itself to actually you know uh give the
answers to the person right
yeah that's an it's such an important
thing to remember I think the the
realization that I had um had I was
talking to a emergency room physician uh
a couple years ago
And one of the things he brought up to
me was even the way that we do analytics
uh for quality reporting um whether it's
for CMS or you know any regulatory
agency um things are based on averages
and one of the things we have to be
keenly aware of is you're not going to
find an individual that looks like the
average that comes from this mountain of
data that people are looking at to
create these the metrics. Um, in a
really risky example that I hadn't
really considered, if you're an
emergency room doctor and you see me
without knowing anything about my
history and you see that I've got a high
blood pressure or, you know, but you
could see my blood sugar seems outside
of a normal range to you based on
averaging.
If you don't know what is normal for me,
you might overreact and prescribe
something that actually can cause an ad,
you know, an unintended adverse
reaction. And and I think, you know,
what what we're talking about is a
really really important area that we
want to make sure that people are
mindful of. Um, you know, if you've got
a podium and we're we're talking to
however many people are going to be
listening to the podcast,
what would you tell people who are
designing AI and designing these models,
large language models that they should
be thinking about? Are there some some
maybe two or three things that you would
tell them that they should really be
doubling down on now while they're
designing that'll help to prevent them
from getting into situations where that
that contextual awareness is just it's
not adequate anymore.
Yeah. I mean um the first thing is like
when you use a model right like you
first need to understand like you know
where and how it was trained right like
what data was it trained upon. Maybe you
use a model right like uh that was
trained on like a data set specific to a
location like US but then the doctors
are in Europe or it might not really
work because like the demographics
change like the
change the diagnosis change a lot of
different things right so when you
design a system you first need to
understand like what model to use and
like what data has it been trained upon
like when you decide to use that model
Um you also need to ensure that you use
it for the right purpose it was intended
to do right like if you're using a
general purpose LLM um you should really
understand that it was just designed for
general purpose and not really uh
something specific to uh you know
designing a medical system medical AI
system right uh so data is important and
the context you bring in um should be as
much thought of as possible right like
it should bring and all possible factors
like I said like a four different
factors like about the human about the
institution about like uh what sort of
problem we solving and if there's a
human that we could defer the defer or
delegate the responsibility to and like
what humans are available right like so
it depends on as much as context as
possible
right
um and again as much good data as
possible right
so you're not recommending people design
without humans in the loop for just
everything.
Not right now. Uh I do uh I mean I think
some of the task right like it depends
on the risk each task has diagnosis has
certain level of risk versus something
like surgery or like making the decision
on this part whether to you know make a
make an incession like 5 mm or 3 mm that
is something like really really uh needs
a human in the loop right um so it
depends on the risk and then like when
they do design and design these AI
systems the models that you use needs to
also incorpor ate like the explanability
and transparency and also uh it and the
third thing is it needs to have good
eval system, good testing mechanisms and
guardrails in place like guardrails are
pretty much the most important thing uh
when it comes to like extremely
regulated compli uh compliance requ uh I
mean required fields like healthcare.
Right. Right. So, as we're wrapping up,
um if if folks wanted to get in touch
with you, um how can they find you?
Um they could uh find me on LinkedIn. Um
yeah, and potentially I I could uh yeah,
LinkedIn is where I'm most active and I
could I would respond by emails as well.
And it's my first name, last name, and
Gmail.
Well, I'll make sure that we put
everything in in the the show notes. So,
if you're you're listening, you want to
reach out to Kashan, uh we'll make that
really easy for you. Mr. Ron, it's been
such a pleasure to have you on on the
sign room and great to meet you here.
I'm excited to continue having some
great conversations the next couple days
while we're here in Las Vegas.
Of course, thank you very very much.
Yeah, thank you. Thank you so much,
Chris. Thank you.
That's it for this episode of the Signal
Room. If today's conversation sparked
something in you, an idea, a challenge,
or a perspective worth amplifying, I'd
love to hear from you. Message me on
LinkedIn or visit signarroompodcast.com
to explore being a guest on an upcoming
episode. Until next time, stay tuned,
stay curious, and stay human.